<tool id="quick_assemble" name="Paired-end pipeline">
	<command interpreter="python"> quick_assemble.py -l $read1 -e $read2 -r $refseq -d $report.files_path $glinear $dgm 
					#if $settings.dset == "asb_full":
						-a $settings.asbtype 
						-i $settings.ins 
						-k $settings.kmers
						$settings.gcircos
					#end if
	</command>
	
	<inputs>
		<param type="data" format="fasta,fastq" name="read1" label="File of Read 1" help="Read_1 in paired-end sequencing" />
		<param type="data" format="fasta,fastq" name="read2" label="File of Read 2" help="Read_2 in paired-end sequencing"/>
		<param type="data" format="fasta" name="refseq" label="Reference genome" />
		<param type="select" name="glinear" label="Create one linear genome sequence" >
			<option value="-m">Yes</option>
			<option selected="True" value="">No</option>
		</param>

		<param type="select" name="dgm" label="Run Digital Normalization">
			<option value="">Yes</option>
			<option value="-c" selected="True">No</option>
		</param>

		<conditional name="settings">
			<param name='dset' type="select" label="Assembly settings">
				<option selected="True" value="asb_default">Default Setting</option>
				<option value="asb_full">Advanced Setting</option>
			</param>

			<when value="asb_full">
				<param type="select" name="asbtype" label="Assembler" >
					<option value="velvet">Velvet</option>
					<option value="vicuna">VICUNA</option>
					<option value="spades">SPAdes</option>
				</param>
				<param type="text" name="kmers" size="30" value="35,45,55,65" label="K-mer size" help="K-mers used in the de novo assemlbly"/>
				<param type="integer" name="ins" size="15" value="350" label="Insert size" help="Insert size for paired-end seuqencing" />
				<param type="select" name="gcircos" label="Whether to create visualization for assembly result" help="Suggestions: Choose no if you have more than 100 contigs in your assembly result">
					<option selected="True" value="">Yes</option>
					<option value="-g">No</option>
				</param>
		
			</when>

			<when value="asb_normal" />
		</conditional>

	</inputs>

	<outputs>
		<data name="target_genome" format="fasta" label="assembled genome on ${on_string}.fasta" from_work_dir="sspace.fasta" />

		<data name="linear_genome" format="fasta" label="linear genome from assembly on ${on_string}.fa" from_work_dir="linear.fasta" >
			<filter>glinear == "-m" </filter>
		</data>	

		<data name="report" format="html" label="Quast report on ${on_string}.html" from_work_dir="quast2show.html"/>
		<data name="varfile" format="vcf" label="variation file on ${on_string}.vcf" from_work_dir="variation.vcf" />
		<data name="comparison" format="txt" label="draft vs.reference comparison, result from ${on_string}.coords" from_work_dir="comparison.final.coords"/>

		<data name="circos" format="pdf" label="circos graph draft vs. reference on ${on_string}" from_work_dir="comparison_circos.pdf" >
		<filter> settings["gcircos"] != "-g"</filter>
		</data>

	</outputs>

 <help>

**Quick Reference**

This runs the entire pipeline of the Virus Assembly Pipeline (VirAmp) with default settings. **For impatient users**, you need at least three files: read#1 and read#2 of shotgun sequencing files in FASTA or FASTQ format, and a reference genome in FASTA format.  If you know the insertion size of your paired-end library, you may also change that number.  Otherwise by default it's set to 350.

------------

**What you will get**

1. A complete assembly normally contains 4~10 contigs, listed in the order of reference genome

2. A comprehensive report evaluating the assembly produced by Quast

3. A SNV report in VCF format, which reports variants between the new assembly and the reference genome

4. A stucture comparison report describing how the new assembly aligned to the reference genome

5. A circos graph visualizing the report of **4**.  When the assembly result contains more than 100 contigs, it is suggested to turn off this option in **Advanced Settings**.

6. (Optional) One linear genome created from the assembly result of **1**.  By default this is not provided.  We strongly recommend to use the result of **1** and look into those gaps before closing them, especially when **1** contains more than 20 contigs.

------------

**VirAmp workflow**

Virus Assembly Pipeline contains a set of programs to assemble the the virus genome from shotgun sequence in a fast and accurate way with a related genome as guide.  In general, it contains the following steps:


1. Quality Control

This step trims out the low quality bases in reads from both end using seqtk toolkit

2. Diginal Normalization

Digital normalization (diginorm) uses a single-pass computational algorithm to reduce the high and redundant coverage in shotgun sequence dataset, thus significantly decreasing time and memory requirements for the de novo assembly while retaining the accuracy.

**Notice**
Since Digital Normalization is designed to deal with extreme high coverage data (x1000 or above), by default it's not turned on. One can choose to turn on at the input panel.


3. De novo assembly (velvet)

This step uses the velvet program to do a de novo assembly from the shotgun sequence. This step results in a set of contigs of various lengths.

4. Reference-guided Scaffolding (AMOScmp)

Contigs generated from velvet in step 3 are oriented and connected into scaffolds by the reference-guided assembly tool AMOScmp

5. Scaffolding using paired-end information (SSPACE)

Uses paired-end reads from the original dataset to extend and scaffold contigs

6. Assembly assessment

QUAST (Quality Assessment Tool for Genome Assemblies) program is used for the statistical assessment of the assemblies resulting from step 4

7. SNV generation

MUMmer is used to align the assembly results to the reference genome and report SNVs.

8. Draft and reference genome comparison

MUMmer is used to compare the assembly results (draft genome) with the reference genome.  

-------------

**Citation**

For more details and citation about each tool, please go to "VirAmp" section and go through each step separately.

 </help>


</tool>

